



# IVAN POZDERAC WEB DEVELOPER

## **ABOUT ME**

Web developer with over 8 years of professional experience in the field. Has an eye for details and website optimisation, strongly believes that UX is the most important part of the app. Always open to test new and emerging technologies to expand his toolbox.

**EMAIL** 

ivan.pozderac@gmail.com

**PHONE** 

+385 97 792 9749

**LINKED IN** 

linkedin.com/in/ivanpozderac



#### **SKILLS**

- JavaScript (ES6, Flow) / Typescript
- HTML5 (also templating with pug, handlebars, liquid, nunjucks)
- CSS3 (variables, Sass, PostCSS, BEM, JSS, styled components, TailwindCSS)
- React (+Redux, hooks, NextJS), Vue, AngularJS
- Storybook (components library, design systems)
- Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, react test library
- Gulp, Webpack, Bower, npm
- Jamstack (CMSs Contentful, Prismic, ButterCMS, Forestry.io, PayloadCMS, Strapi, FrontMatter, SSGs - Eleventy, NextJS, Gatsby)
- version control git CLI (GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket)
- inline SVG and SVG optimization
- responsive web design and cross browser compatibility
- comfortable working with Invision, Zepplin and Figma
- interactions with REST API and GraphQL
- Node/Express/MongoDB side projects experience
- Various third party service integrations
- experience working in agile environments and teams
- experience with Jira, Confluence, Asana, Tempo
- art of giving/receiving constructive feedback
- always looking for improvements
- Googling skills

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### WEB DEVELOPER 09/2021 - 06/2023

Dept Agency, Dublin, Ireland

- Improved and optimised interactive website that is written in technology I had never seen before
- Improved editor experience by adding custom components written in PIKE language - it was my first PIKE experience



# WORK EXPERIENCE

- Made PoC in order to research best approaches regarding code structure, choice for styling and bundling for small project that had to be optimised and small in size
- Wrote documentation about my findings and put some suggestions with strong arguments why something should or shouldn't be used in order to save development time
- Improved user flow on NextJS based projects
- Refactored the whole project and removed ton of dependencies as developer on the project wasn't reading my suggestions that I made for PoC so it was bloated and non-functional. Refactoring resulted in project being able to be bundled and overall size was decreased for about 40%
- Worked on numerous custom projects for global brand and its subbrands with opinionated starter kit made with NextJS

#### WEB DEVELOPER, PROJECT MANAGER 01/2020 - 07/2021

Aphix Software Ltd, Drogheda, Ireland

- Led the initiative of introducing the component library to unify the look and feel of the company products and implemented it
- Taken lead position in preventing future bug-fest with BDD by writing Gherkins and doing manual testing of the app
- Prevented bad deploys by adding additional layer of protection for product release by implementing automated testing
- Improved UX and DX by refactoring legacy code and eliminating a lot of bugs in the process
- Pitched few ideas about how to change agile processes that significantly improved DX resulting in overall better time management inside the team, less interruptions and scheduling meetings in blocks rather that having small and unproductive gaps in the schedule
- Improved quality of product by introducing crash and bug analysis tool which helped us discover some silent issues while using the app
- Regularly raising awareness about technical debt inside the team and company-wide
- My productive talk with CTO resulted in him deciding to transform
   Aphix platform to the ESB as it will help the platform to be more



## WORK EXPERIENCE

- stable, easier to use and communicate with 3rd party service providers and different ERP's
- Suggesting improvements on regular basis where I could see room for it both on frontend and backend
- Took over project management role for project including University
  in Northern Ireland. Was included in communication with all parties,
  prepared presentations and reports on team's progress. Every quarter I
  am presenting progress to the University project board on online
  meetings and promoting Aphix quality improvements making sure
  that all included parties are up to date.
- Tried to push the idea of having same code style inside the team and implementing linters and pre-commit hooks to be confident that bad code won't go to the production several times

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**, 11/2017 - 11/2019

COBE Tech, Osijek, Croatia

- Saved about 10% of developers' time on different projects by introducing good Javascript code practices and same coding style for all members of the team with unit tests, implementing types, linters and pre-commit hooks
- Accelerated and automated deployment process by building failsafe pipelines (trough Travis-CI and Heroku) which resulted in team having 5% more time to concentrate on coding instead of deployment
- Increased project velocity by discussing UI/UX in advance with designers in order to eliminate possible misunderstandings and need to do the same thing twice in later stages of the sprint
- Saved time on both frontend and backend implementation by participating in design of the REST API responses, often going for solutions that are simple enough for both sides to implement
- Improved loading times on several websites by auditing and optimizing code, assets and number of requests
- Shaved off 4 seconds of COBE website's loading time by implementing Gatsby static site generator with headless CMS
- Expanded toolset by trying new things like ES6+, JSS, styled components, Flow and Typescript which resulted in writing code better, faster and easier



## WORK EXPERIENCE

- Significantly improved DX (developer experience) and velocity on internal projects by refactoring weak codebases, improving project structure, updating dependencies, automating deployment process and enforcing good code practices
- Participated in code reviews and reviewed code on pull requests to ensure all team members follow the same coding style and using good coding practices
- Participated in various workshops and talks, held talks about headless
   CMS, CSS and git

#### **FRONTEND DEVELOPER**, 06/2015 - 11/2017

MONO Software, Osijek, Croatia

- Improved DX (developer experience) by designing and implementing different AngularJS starting kits for Baasic (backend as a service tool) which helped all developers using the tool to dive in the ways it should be used
- Implemented and coded UI which improved UX for several monolith applications that are used by end users
- Removed more than 60% of unnecessary CSS code in big AngularJS app which made it work faster

#### **GRAPHIC UI/UX DESIGNER**, 11/2014 - 05/2015

Freelance graphic and UI/UX designer, Osijek, Croatia

- Designed logotypes, websites and UI with good UX practices in mind
- Prepared designs for print for various products, brochures and posters
- Worked as subcontractor for local companies

#### **WEB DESIGNER - VOLUNTEER**, 09/2014 - 11/2014

Ofir Ltd., Osijek, Croatia

 Designed and developed several websites including eCommerce solutions where I gained professional experience of working with clients



#### **COMM&IM TEAM MEMBER / IM MANAGER**, 11/2010 - 06/2012

Student Organization AIESEC, Local committee Osijek, Croatia

- Experienced working in teams and learned to be a team player
- Learned how to give and receive constructive feedback
- Gained experience in leading small team, learned to rely on others and to delegate tasks as well as working with people from around the world

# LATEST PROJECTS

#### **NEXT JS BRAND WEBSITES**, 09/2022 - 06/2023

Working on the platform project for globally recognised company that has numerous brands. Building sites and maintaining existing ones as needed.

My responsibilities:

- Fixing issues and polishing unfinished features
- Doing the whole projects with NextJS starter kits that are later customised to cater each brand and their needs, sometimes it was eCommerce website that is connected to Shopify
- Communicating with the external DevOps team to fix the pipeline or to fix something in the system that client is using for deploying new websites as we don't have access to all parts of the system
- Fixing the DevOps pipelines myself when possible
- Fixing third party system by pinpointing the bugs and explicitly showing why something unexpected is happening - this was huge issue for a lot of our websites
- Adjusting the whole pre-built system for unexpected data sources
- Managing 3rd party services like Algolia

## **PREACT WIDGET**, 09/2023 - 01/2023

Bundled to a single JavaScript file that is distributed and used as a widget on niche websites. It dynamically loads data from the API and shows the data to the visitors on the website.

My responsibilities:

Make PoC for research and write docs and suggestions



# LATEST PROJECTS

 Refactoring the whole project as there was ton of unnecessary dependencies and code was too abstracted which resulted in final build being optimised and smaller in size

#### **STATIC/DYNAMIC WEBSITE**, 09/2021 - 09/2022

Governmental body website built on exotic technology that I never heard of before. NDA prohibits me to talk more.

My responsibilities:

- Refactoring the gaps in the logic and finishing unfinished features
- Fixing bugs with third party services in server side XSLT
- Adding new modules written in PIKE
- Adding reactive functionalities in VueJS

## APP FOR SALES REPRESENTATIVES, 01/2020 - 07/2021

Tablet app with helpful features that enable sales reps to do quick orders when selling on the field. Works offline and syncs when network is available.

My responsibilities:

- Refactoring the whole project as it was written in vanilla JS
- Fixing UI discrepancies and functional bugs
- Adding BDD to the project
- Giving ideas for new features to improve the product
- Supporting students on the internship

#### **POCKETSHOP**, 01/2020 - 07/2021

Mobile app for iOS and Android phones that helps people in retail order products to fill their stock. Works offline as some of the underground storages block the internet signal. You are able to scan barcodes and make an offline order and soon as you connect to network the order is sent.

My responsibilities:

• Ensuring the **quality of the product** by implementing BDD



# LATEST PROJECTS

- Preparing implementation of automated test pipeline
- Creating reports and presenting progress every quarter
- Implementing new features and fixing bugs
- Helping team members when needed

## SURVEILLANCE WEB PROJECT, 06/2019 - 11/2019

Dashboard where you can manage and configure all things considering video surveillance system.

My responsibilities:

- Configuring tslint, storybook, defining structure of the project
- Coding UI with React styled components in TypeScript
- Coding Storybook stories that helped other developers to see how component should be implemented
- Writing tests in Jest and Enzyme for unit testing and React test library for testing UI (styled components)

## **COBE TECH STATIC WEBSITE**, 04/2019 - 09/2019

Switched our old website to **static site generator Gatsby** and connected it to **Prismic headless CMS**.

My responsibilities:

- Researching the headless CMS solutions that would fit our requirements
- Setting up project from the scratch with Gatsby
- Connecting Gatsby with Prismic headless CMS

#### **SMART PRODUCT ADMIN PANEL**, 03/2019 - 07/2019

Admin panel is connected with REST API which is central data point for smart product, admin panel and mobile apps. Admin panel is used to collect statistics about the users, smart product and also to manage content that is shown in mobile apps.

My responsibilities:

Configuring styles with Material-UI and JSS instead of Sass

- Adding and configuring eslint and flow to have better development experience with JavaScript
- Writing tests in Jest and Enzyme for unit testing

More detailed list of projects I worked on can be found on **my LinkedIn profile** 

## **EDUCATION**

MASTER'S DEGREE.

Department of Information Sciences, 09/2012 University of Josip Juraj Strossmayer, Osijek, Croatia

BACHELOR'S DEGREE.

Department of Information Sciences, 09/2009 University of Josip Juraj Strossmayer, Osijek, Croatia

## **LANGUAGES**

- CROATIAN, native
- **ENGLISH**, high proficiency (spoken and written)

# CAREER INTERESTS

I have interest in **Jamstack** and basically all **new emerging web technologies**. I like to learn new things and I am very adaptable to the different technologies and programming languages - if there's documentation available, I can pull it off. My aim is to be full fledged **fullstack JS web developer** with really strong skills in both fields (being comfortable equally with databases and CSS). Lately I wrote some Python3 scripts and seriously considering taking a deeper dive into Python.

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

Besides programming, open source software, going to programming meet ups, workshops and conferences, I'm also very interested in electronics, fighter jet DIY models, music, TCGs, board and video games. I am Nintendo fanboy, tough Street Fighter opponent, Ace Combat pilot, Warrior of time who enjoys nerd trivia as well as Exploding kittens while listening to some good new retrowave or old school rock & metal.